Carlos Daniel Jiménez M.

Colombia

🛮 (+57) 322-816-9956 | 🗷 danieljimenez88m@gmail.com | 🏕 www.danieljimemezm.com | 🖸 carlosjimenez88M | 🛅 djimenezm

Summary_

Experienced Senior Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer with a demostrated history of working in Startups, and public institutions (Chile-Colombia-USA), I build Computational and Cognitive tools to make real world applications on Data Science, Machine Learning and Al. Skilled in Bayesian Data Analysis, Machine Learning applications , Statistical Modeling, Data Visualization, Lineal Algrebra , Markdown and LaTeX.

Work Experience

Chiper Bogotá-Colombia

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST currently

- Build statistical models that allow knowing the needs of users
- Research the applications of Data Science.
- Developing Machine learning applications
- · Validated behavioral models on multiple datasets.
- Business Intelligence
- Implementing predictive maintenance tools using machine learning.

Merlin Jobs USA-Col

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST Aug. 2019 - Nov 2019

- Developer and implementer Machine Learning models
- · Research the applications of Data Science.
- Helping drive the strategic direction and priorities as solidify merlin as a top data science company in USA
- I Conducted customer interviews to understand their needs and help drive our data products strategy
- Develop models that translate unstructured client data into valuable insights

Resolve Studio Bogotá-Colombia

CHIEF DATA SCIENCE AND DATA ENGINEERING

Jan 2019- Aug 2019

- Lead Data Scientist and Machine Learning developer for autonomous attributions campaings with Deep Learnning and another technologies
- Developed Data Science models solutions for classification and Data Analysis
- · Lead Data Science Team for automate solutions and tasks throughout the company such as client sales prediction, demand forecast

Big Bang Data Bogotá - Medellín , Colombia

PRE SALES ENGINEER AND DATA SCIENTIST

Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2019

- · lead sales of products based on data and machine learning
- · Developed Machine Learning models for: Marketing, Pricing, forecast, and Churn with differents clients
- Evaluated and Creator of work methodology

Secretaria de Educación Distrital

Bogotá - Colombia

DATA SCIENTIST Aug 2017 - Aug 2018

- Data Scientist on an advanced analytics team working in education projects and innovations in big data tools (RStudio and Hadoop)
- Build and own complex data pipelines using SQL and other data processing tools • I Created sampling model for Evaluated Educational Progress

Superintendencia de Puertos y Transporte

Bogotá - Col

STATITICIAN AND QUANTITATIVE ANALYST

2017

- Created BI and tools that identify opportunities and some risk for projects
- · Worked with other departments to use new technologies to streamline Goverment policies and rules
- · Developed a Mac and Windows python application for Policies evaluation software to measure employee productivity.

Puedo ser Consulting Group

Bogotá - Col

Jan 2017 - Sep 2017

• I developed of Statistics Models to: Clusters, Marketing Analytics and Forecast

• I created Statistics department

CHIEF STATISTICS

New Port Negocios Internacionales

Bogotá - Colombia

March 2014 - Apr 2015

NEW PORT INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS

- Researched on strategies to optimize pickup planning in warehouses
- Support Data Science initiatives across the company
- · Research the applications of AI in Marketing

DANIEL JIMÉNEZ · RÉSUMÉ APRIL 25, 2020

Invershop SAS Bogotá - Col

Marketing' Chief

Marc 2012- March 2014

- Researched on technologies to create scalable multi-tenant software Marketing
- Developing of intelligent reporting for supporting the Marketing management team
- Creation and development of Machine Learning algorithms for Marketing Strategies

ONU - Secretaria de Desarrollo Económico 'La Pintana'

Chile

ASSOCIATE ECONOMIST 2012

- · I Researched and analyze labor market conditions, national and MSA patterns, and past and future market trends and forecasts
- I created Psychology Test for Social development
- I Worked with media to customize Growth Destiny's data and insights for their stories/inquiries

Academic Experience _____

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Bogotá, Col

PROFESSOR

Dic 2019 - Currently

- Manager and creator program's on Data Science and Big Data
- Data engineering teacher (with Python)

Uniempresarial Bogotá, Co

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR

March 2018 - Occasionally

- Courses Creator on Data Sciene, BI, Computational Science and Econometrics for Business
- · Academic Consultat on Metacognition
- Teacher subjects on university levels :Big Data, Computational Science, Statistics and Data Analysis

Educación FuturoBogotá- Colombia

PRINCIPAL PROFESSOR May 2015- Apr 2016

- · Teacher at the chair of Statistics and KPI's
- Courses Creator on law of the unemployed: Innovation Diploma and Business Computing

UniAsturias Spain-México

ECONOMICS PROFESSOR 201

• Full professor in following subjects: Microeconomics, Political Theory, Asian Economics, Economics History and Mathematical Economics

Education

Santo Tomás University

M.S. IN STATISTICS

Bogotá - Col

Jan 2018 - 2020

M.S. IN STATISTICS

• focus in : Bayesian Statistics , EDA and Machine Learning Applied

Michigan University Usa

Master Course in Machine Learning

Apr. 2020 - Currently

• Focus in : Data Science with applications on Emprirical Bayes

Santo Tomás University

Bogotá - Col

B.A IN ECONOMICS

Jan 2010 - Dec 2014

• Focus in : Maths for Economics

Tools

Programming:Python: +4, R: +9, Octave:+3, Matlab:+2

Data Science: Tidymodels, keras, Tenserflow, Scikit Learn, tidyverse, Spark, Bigquery, MySQL

Development: Docker, Git, Google Cloud Platform, Plumber, Flask.

Visualization: Shiny, looker, Power BI.

Areas of Interest

Applied Machine Learning, Natural Lenguage Processing, Statistical modelling, Bayesian data analysis, Web Scrapping, Forecasting and Deep Learning.

Publications

Inferencia estadística un enfoque moderno

www.danieljimenezm.com

FREE

• Design of the theoretical framework of the application of statistical inference applied to data science

Extracurricular Activity

danieljiemezm.com Colombia

BLOGGER Aug 2018 - currently

Blog on Applied Statistics, Data Analysis and Machine Learning with R

Nostradamusdata.com Col-Chile

TEACHER Jun-2019- currently

Special Professor on Data Science and BI